前情提要
黑客軍團
進去了
第一季 第四集
ZiMuZu
傾情奉獻
黑衣章魚X  辰星曉Reginamoon
翻譯
showeryhe   分裂草
不高興童鞋
翻譯
杏仁斯嘉麗
薛定諤的貓
時間軸
Kallen
校對
神經草
特效&后期
寶寶
顧問
somehacker
總監
草society
鋼山  黑客困境
Steel Mountain. The hacker's dilemma.
你如何摧毀完全
What to do when a bunch of data you want to destroy
不聯網的數據
is completely off the grid?
你好  邪惡公司  我們是去社會
Hello, Evil Corp. We are fsociety.
風云人物  行個屈膝禮吧
Man of the hour. Take a curtsy.
黑暗軍團
Dark Army?
他們毫無準則  做任何人的雇傭黑客
They got no code. They hack for anyone:
恐怖分子  北朝  伊朗  俄國
terrorists, North Korea, Iran, Russia--
走過路過不要錯過  我的專輯出爐了
Yo, yo, yo, yo, my album just dropped.
來買張CD吧
Please buy my CD.
他掌握了我的銀行賬戶  奧利
He has my bank account, Ollie.
我們不能為此就感染眾安的網絡
We cannot just infect Allsafe's network because of this.
能說下計劃嗎
Can we please hear the plan?
鋼山那邊現在進展如何
Where are we at with Steel Mountain?
我知道要如何摧毀備份而不必炸管道了
I know how to take out the backups without blowing up the pipeline.
正常人難過的時候會做什么
What do normal people do when they get this sad?
大概是去找朋友家人吧
They reach out to friends or family.
我嗑嗎啡
I do morphine.
就這些了
There it is.
找  刮  碾了那么久
After all the searching, scraping, dusting,
就剩下這些了
That's all that's left.
一條線  最后的一條
One line. The last line.
此時此刻  是揭發維拉  結識機器人先生
The consequences of busting Vera and meeting Mr. Robot,
創造你  以及所有一切的結果
creating you--everything till now, this moment.
這是我的選擇  是我選擇了這一切
I chose this. I chose all this.
像鋼山這樣的數據存儲中心
Data storage facilities like Steel Mountain--
使用LTO-9存儲標準
it's linear-tape open standard 9.
一種磁帶存儲技術
溫度限制在16到35攝氏度
Temp value between 61 and 95.
磁帶上的氧化鐵顆粒
Iron oxide in mag tape--
通過粘合劑固定在聚氨酯帶基上
it sticks to polyurethane with a binder.
如果室溫超過了35攝氏度上限
If hvac conditions surpass the ceiling 95 degrees,
聚氨酯膠粘劑軟化松脫  數據將無法讀取
polyurethane adhesive mollifies and tape data is unreadable.
這就是我們要做的
This is what we're doing.
將這塊電路板裝在恒溫器后
This circuit board, if installed behind a thermostat,
我們就能植入專用后門
it lets us plant an asymmetric back door
在鋼山的專用網絡上建立一個VPN
then create a VPN in the Steel Mountain intranet.
我們都知道樹莓派[卡式計算機]是什么
Okay, we all know what a Raspberry Pi is.
你想說什么
What's your point?
他想黑進鋼山的氣候控制系統
He wants to hack Steel Mountain's climate control system,
升高整個中心的溫度  毀掉所有磁帶
raise the facility's heat high enough to destroy all the tapes.
你認為把這玩意安在恒溫器后就足夠了嗎
And you think sticking this behind the thermostat will do all that?
只要有專門設計的軟件就行
With the right software specifically designed.
我這就調出我對這個中心的研究
I'll pull up my research on the facility,
看看哪個恒溫器最容易得手
start targeting which thermostats are the most accessible.
你們說得倒挺輕松
Yeah, well, that's all well and good,
但還是得有人進入那破地方
but we still gotta get in the damn joint.
就在這里  在阿迪朗達克山脈深處
There. Deep in the Adirondacks.
占地145英畝以上  以前是一個石灰礦井
In 145-plus acre former limestone mine.
3噸重的鋼制大門  武裝警衛全天候巡邏
3-ton steel gates, 24/7 armed guards,
閉路監控  還有網絡運行中心工作人員
closed circuit cameras, NOC staffing.
真不想直接炸了嗎
Sure you don't want to just blow it up?
只要找到一個安保漏洞就行
All we need is one security flaw.
你自己看看  就是建成零漏洞的
Look at this place, man. It was built not to have any.
我就看到...6個到處走的漏洞
I see about... six walking around.
你還好嗎
You okay, man?
怎么個意思
What the hell?
你要去哪
Where you going?
事說完了  不是嗎
We're done, aren't we?
戒斷反應差不多該出現了
That was about the time the withdrawal started.
記得嗎
Remember?
我知道  我違反了自己的規則
I know--I broke my own rule.
但我沒有賽寶松
But I have no suboxone.
我只有抑郁癥  社交恐懼癥
What I do have--clinical depression, social anxiety.
白天上班  晚上接著忙  私人關系一團糟
A day job, a night job, confusing relationships.
還有那些指望我的人
Others depending on me.
以及扳倒世界上最大的公司的目標
Taking down the largest corporation in the world.
都是我自己選的
And I chose it all.
我這輩子  這條線都在試圖控制我
This line has wanted to own me my whole life.
它們在墨西哥被生物合成出來  制成藥片
Biosynthesized in some lab in Mexico, packed into a pill,
再裝箱運到美國  分揀包裝
shipped to the states where it was packaged
印上商標  政府再抽稅
with a logo and taxed by the government,
然后被受賄的警衛偷走  賣給了維拉的嘍啰
stolen by a bribed guard, sold to a Vera henchman,
倒手給夏拉  然后再賣給我
then oversold to Shayla, and then to me.
它需要我  正如我需要它
It needs me just as much as I need it.
這一刻是注定了的  每一個選擇都推動著我
The moment was destined, every choice bringing me
向這條線邁進一步
closer to this one line.
這條線  是最后的一條
This line. This last line.
我保證
I promise.
今天會是最難受的一天
Today will be the worst of it.
熬過接下來的幾天  我就徹底戒了
Get through the next couple days, and then I'll be clean.
你想怎樣
What do you want?
是我  快開門
It's me, open up.
我本不想勞您大駕給我開門
I would have saved you the trip to the door
但你又不希望我闖進來什么的
but you're all, like, against me breaking in or whatever.
你來干什么
Why are you here?
你的小計劃羅梅洛有了新看法
Romero got some clarity on your little plan
需要你親自過去商量
that's gonna need your undivided.
-那好  我們走  -你這是怎么了
- Okay, let's go. - What's going on with you?
看著跟快死了似的
You look like shit.
我沒事
I'm fine.
我跟你說  這個計劃行不通的
Look, man. This plan's not gonna work.
為什么
Why? Why is that?
我對鋼山進行偵查
I was doing recon on Steel Mountain.
發現了個問題  大問題
Came up with a problem. A big, fat one.
邪惡公司正在升級他們的安保協議
Evil Corp's upping their security protocol.
要我說他們有點反應過度  但手段有效
If you ask me, it's overkill, but it's legit.
我說過  他們不是無懈可擊
I already told you, they have their vulnerabilities.
我們黑了紐約的中心然后怎么辦
So what happens after we hack the New York facility?
然后我們還得去一趟納什維爾
Then we have to take a trip to Nashville,
然后再去科羅拉多  去圣何塞
then Colorado, then San Jose,
然后再去該死的塔拉哈西
then goddamn Tallahassee.
這可不妙  大事不妙
Ugh, this looks real bad. Real bad.
他們準備把所有數據的模擬備份
They are physically copying then shipping
復制轉運到各地
all the analog backups.
全國各地五個規模極大安保極嚴的后備中心
Five big-ass fortress-like redundancies across the country.
假如  我只是說假如
Now maybe--and it was always a big maybe--
我們能成功潛入一個  也不可能都能闖進去
we get into one, but no way we get into all of them.
我們剛剛燒糊了其中一個
The minute we fry one facility,
他們就會立即升級其它所有中心的溫控
they'll patch every climate control system they own.
不管你用什么手段  這個計劃都行不通
No matter how you slice it, the plan is DOA.
你從哪得到的消息
Where'd you get this?
你這話什么意思
What the hell do you mean?
我們還在邪惡公司的網絡里呢
We're still in Evil Corp's network.
該死
Shit.
提利爾說的就是這個
This is what Tyrell was talking about.
你剛說什么
What'd you just say?
提利爾  那個提利爾·威利克
Tyrell? As in Tyrell Wellick?
對
Yeah.
你什么時候和邪惡公司的首席技術官
Since when did you and the goddamn CTO
成了好哥們了
of Evil Corp become, what, chums?
他說4月1日才會進行升級
Says this isn't happening till April 1st.
今天是29號
It's only the 29th.
我們還有幾天
We still got a few days.
還有時間
We have time.
所有的磁帶還都存在紐約的中心里
All their tapes are still in the New York facility.
也就是說  我們今天就得行動
Just means we go up today.
但我們根本沒準備好
We're nowhere close to being ready.
我已經下載好了所需的樓層平面圖
Well, I've already downloaded all the necessary PDFs of the floor plans
來定位目標恒溫器
to target the thermostats.
得好好計劃一下
It will require some planning,
但我在車上就能搞定
But nothing I can't do in the car.
我應該很快就能控制那里的監控和數據采集網絡
It shouldn't take me long to own the facility's scada network.
尤其有人幫忙的話
Especially with some help.
你們去實地
You guys hit the road
特倫頓幫我完成軟件部署
while Trenton helps me finish the distro.
我們會加速完成的
We'll double-time it.
你們一到那里就能從FTP服務器上下載了
You can get it off the FTP server as soon as you get there.
中國那邊怎么辦
What about China?
周二之前我們就得完成入侵
We'd have to execute the hack before Tuesday.
不用擔心中國那邊
Don't worry about China.
你們一走我就聯系我黑暗軍團的聯絡人
I'll hit up my Dark Army contact as soon as you take off.
你就這樣"聯系"
Oh, you just gonna hit up
世界上最危險的黑客團體嗎
the world's most dangerous hacker crew?
你們是集體失心瘋了
Ya'll have gone and misplaced your collective minds.
這事我們計劃了幾個月了
We've been planning this for months.
現在我們就憑他一句話  就說走就走嗎
Now we're gonna go up on a lark just 'cause he said so?
這計劃太爛了
This plan is shit.
這計劃會成功的
The plan will work.
等我們到了那里
And once we're actually there,
我還需要準備社交工程I still need to prep the social engineering,
非技術性入侵  通過社交達到欺騙等目的
而且我們還不知道具體誰進去
plus we have no idea who physically's gonna go in.
這是我的計劃  我進去
It's my plan. I'll go in.
聽著  伙計  你...
Look, man, you...
你也許能瞞過這些呆子
You might be able to hide it from these nerds,
但我一眼就能認出癮君子
but I know a junkie when I see one.
你這種狀態什么也做不了
In your condition, you ain't gonna do Jack or Jill
只會狂吐不止
except puke your brains out
或者給人打飛機  換毒品來爽一把
or give hand jobs for another high.
就像你之前說的
Like you said,
三天之后  一個鋼山就會變成五個
in three days, one Steel Mountain becomes five.
那樣任何計劃都行不通了
That's no good for any plan.
這家伙不太對勁
Something ain't right about this guy.
是啊  但他都領著我們走到這一步了
Yeah, well. He's gotten us this far.
就算這樣  我還是不信任他
Still, I don't trust him.
這和信任無關  記得嗎
Well, it's not about trust, remember?
謝謝你  媽媽
Thank you, mom.
-給你  -好的
- There it is. - All right.
到爸爸這兒來
Come to daddy.
伙計
Yo, man.
你不發表下意見嗎
You gonna say anything about this?
有什么好說的
What's there to say?
看起來一切都在你掌控之中
You seem to have everything under control.
是啊  好吧
Yeah. Okay.
這不是我的行動
This isn't my operation.
我之前就告訴過你了
I told you before.
你是整件事的關鍵
You're the key to the whole thing.
你是這里唯一的自然之力
You're the only force of nature at play here.
有這么一種說法
There's a saying.
魔鬼最強之時
The devil's at his strongest
就是我們不聞不問之時
while we're looking the other way,
就像我們忙其他事的時候
like a program running in the background silently,
在后臺默默運行的程序
while we're busy doing other shit.
后臺程序  是這么稱呼的
Daemons, they call them.
它們無需用戶操作就能運行
They perform action without user interaction.
監視  記錄  通知
Monitoring, logging, notifications.
原始的沖動
Primal urges,
被壓抑的記憶
repressed memories,
不自覺的習慣
unconscious habits.
它們一直都在  一直處于活躍狀態
They're always there, always active.
我們可以試著行善
We can try to be right,
我們可以試著做好人
we can try to be good,
我們可以試著發揮影響
we can try to make a difference,
但這都是無用功
but it's all bullshit.
因為意圖是無關緊要的
'Cause intentions are irrelevant.
它們無法驅使我們  后臺程序卻可以
They don't drive us. Daemons do.
至于我  我的后臺程序比大部分人都多
And me? I've got more than most.
我只是需要休息一下  我會沒事的
I just need to rest a minute, okay? I'll be fine.
放屁  再過幾個小時
Bullshit--a couple hours,
你只會比現在更難受
you'll wish you felt as shitty as you do right now.
等會兒你驚厥發作
Wait till the convulsions start.
你會全身疼痛  又尿又吐  然后...
Full body pains, leaking from everywhere, then--
會對光線和聲音格外敏感
Hypersensitivity to brightness and sound.
再之后是高度妄想
After that, overwhelming paranoia
然后就將陷入抑郁的陰霾
followed by the darkest of depressions.
這些癥狀可能會持續兩周
Symptoms may persist for two weeks,
如果我能撐那么久的話
assuming I last that long.
我知道等著我的是什么
Yeah, I know what's in store.
羅梅洛說得沒錯
Romero may have a point.
你挨過去之前  什么都做不了
You're not gonna be good for anything till you kick this.
燒得慌
I...It burns.
不要生我的氣
Don't be mad at me.
我是犯了錯  但我馬上就要改變世界了
I know I slipped, but I'm about to change the world.
我馬上就要改變世界了
I'm about to change the world.
該死
Shit.
我就喜歡早上這樣醒來
Mm, that is the way I like to get up in the morning.
在床上喝咖啡吃早餐算什么
Screw coffee or breakfast in bed.
如果我每天最先看到的
The first thing I could see every day
是你的性感小屁屁
is that sweet butt of yours.
那我就是這里最幸福的人了
I'd be the happiest dude in the city.
你要出門嗎  寶貝
Are you going somewhere, babe?
嗯  我要去和我爸吃早午餐
Yeah, um, I'm gonna meet my dad for brunch.
什么  別去啊
What? No, babe.
我想帶你去吃早午餐的
I was gonna take you to brunch.
我知道咱倆現在的關系
I mean, I know that things are, like, okay
還算可以  但我不會
between us right now, but I'm--I'm not
就這么輕易原諒自己的
gonna let myself off easy, all right?
我會一直讓你吃香的喝辣的
You will be wined, and you will be dined
直到我覺得自己已經重獲青睞了
until I feel I've gotten myself out of the doghouse.
那咱們今晚去做點什么吧
Well, we can do something tonight, then.
很好
Perfect.
-好了  -別嘛
- Okay. - No.
艾略特在嗎  我給他發過短信
Is Elliot around? I tried texting him.
但他沒回我
Uh, he didn't text me back.
他今天不在
Yeah, he's gone for the day,
所以我才要照顧小鰭
which is why I'm on Flipper duty.
他去哪了
Where is he?
我怎么知道
Shit if I know.
我從不過問細節
I mean, I don't ask details,
再說他也只會告訴我他想說的
but he only ever tells me what he wants anyway, right?
我會告訴他你來過
And I'll tell him you stopped by.
要不要跟我們一起去
Do you want to walk with us?
小鰭尿尿的時候最喜歡有人看了
Flipper loves an audience when she pees.
好啊  反正我
Sure. Yeah. I gotta...
也得走回地鐵站
head back towards the subway anyway.
我們從來不計劃路線的
Oh, we don't plan our path.
我們都是隨便逛逛  隨心情走
I mean, we just kind of wing it and see where the moment takes us.
跟上
Come on.
走啦  要不她要噴發了
Come on, before she bursts.
或許這都是有意的
Maybe this was all intentional.
我的潛意識正在后臺運轉
My subconscious, running in the background,
使我懷疑我哄別人相信的東西
making me doubt what I got everyone else to believe in.
讓我變成自己所懼怕事物的實體體現
Turning me into the physical manifestation of my fear
也就是...
of being a...
廢物
Goddamn waste.
給他一晚來恢復  好吧
Just give him a night to recover, okay?
-明天也來得及  -這狀態得持續一周
- We still have tomorrow. - This shit'll last a week.
我才不想浪費時間照顧病人
And I refuse to waste my time playing nurse.
我們得回去重新部署  考慮后備計劃
We gotta get back, regroup, start devising a plan b.
兔子進入管理系統了
The rabbit is in the administration system.
-來一劑流感疫苗  -兔子  流感疫苗
- Send a flu shot. - Rabbit, flu shot...
-有人嗎  請回答  -兔子在自我復制
- Someone talk to me. - A rabbit replicates
直到文件超載  之后會癌癥一樣傳播
till it overloads a file, then it spreads like cancer.
癌癥
Cancer?
好萊塢式的黑客臆想
Hollywood hacker bullshit.
我干這行27年了
I been in this game 27 years.
從來沒遇到過動畫音樂病毒
Not once have I ever come across an animated singing virus.
《電子世界爭霸戰》
我也沒見過特隆城那樣的文件夾結構
I have yet to fly through a Tron city directory structure.
我敢打賭  現在肯定有編劇在努力寫一部電視劇
I bet you right now some writer's working hard on a TV show
把這一代黑客文化的概念亂搞一通
that'll mess up this generation's idea of hacker culture.
可以直接找我要嘛  小偷
All you had to do is ask, klepto.
我更新了FTP
I've updated the FTP.
文件都準備好了
All the files are ready.
-我創建了...  -他們有消息嗎
- I've created... - Any word from the road?
天哪  已經足足24小時了
Jesus, it's been a full 24 hours.
他們能去哪呢
Where the hell could they be?
有止痛藥嗎
Got any Advil?
你沒去聯系中國那邊嘍
I'm guessing you didn't make contact.
沒有
Nope.
可能這個計劃太大了
Perhaps this plan was a little too ambitious.
我們先等其他人回來
We'll wait until the rest of them get back
然后重新評估情況
and then reevaluate.
無能為力地坐在這兒  等著完蛋嗎
Sitting here helpless while we crash and burn?
不是我的風格
Not my speed.
即使他們黑進了鋼山
Even if they hack into steel mountain,
我們也要同時攻擊中國的數據中心
we need to hit China's data centers simultaneously.
如果黑暗軍團不照做
If the Dark Army isn't compliant,
那我們也無能為力
then there's not much we can do.
天...該死
God... Shit!
我喝大了  都忘了今天是周日
I got so wasted, I forgot it's Sunday.
我知道我的人在哪
I know where my guy will be.
這樣好嗎
Is that wise?
這些人可不怎么體諒人
Those guys aren't known for being the most understanding.
如果他想聯系我們
I'm assuming if he wanted contact--
現在是我想聯系他們
What about what I want?
我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
不必了
No, thank you.
你待在這兒  等他們上FTP
You stick around, wait for the boys to FTP it.
特倫頓
Hey, Trenton.
給你
Here.
-這是什么  -就這最后兩顆了
- What is this? - Come on, they're my last two.
是搖頭丸嗎
Is this ecstasy?
不是  是"明白藥"
No, it's clarity.
能讓你看明白你現在的煩惱
It'll help you see past whatever's bringing you down.
抱歉  我不想無禮
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be rude.
但我不吸毒
I...don't do drugs.
我是抽點大麻
I mean, I-I smoke weed--
抱歉  但是不能還給我
Well, sorry, but there's no take-backs, so...
再說  難道你不想想明白你的心事嗎
Besides, don't you want to figure your shit out?
有時候  如果我遇到什么難事
For me, sometimes when I'm going through something,
我就...怎么說呢
just gotta--I don't know.
先忘卻它一陣子
Forget about it for a little while.
你不是真在喝氣泡水吧
Are you seriously drinking a goddamn sparkling water right now?
要不是你系著我的圍巾  我就揍你了
If you weren't wearing my scarf, I'd kick your ass.
我們還是走吧
I think we should go.
相信我  他每周日都來這兒
Trust me--he's here every Sunday, okay?
他會來的
He'll show.
天啊  羅梅洛  我們該怎么辦
Jesus Christ, Romero. What are we gonna do?
我們把他扔到哪家醫院
We dump him at a hospital,
再想其他辦法
come up with an alternative course of action.
這是我們唯一的選擇
That's our only option.
不行  不能去醫院
No. No hospital.
那我們就走人  管他呢
Then we split. Screw it.
你自己也總這么說
I mean, you say it all the time yourself,
每次革命都要流血犧牲
there's casualties in every revolution.
只有結果是最重要的
All that matters is the end result.
我們沒時間帶著累贅
We got no time to haul dead weight.
好吧  你想走  走吧
Fine! You wanna leave, leave.
去你的
Screw this, man.
我得嗑一發
I need a hit.
我會好起來的
I'll be better.
讓我挺過去就行
Just to get me through this.
我不能讓你那么做
I can't let you do that.
就嗑一發
One hit.
能讓我重新上路就行
You know, just to get me back on the road.
我們沒時間了
We don't have time. This...
我們得馬上行動
needs to happen now.
就一發
One hit.
來吧
Come on.
走吧
Let's go.
打擾一下  伙計
Excuse me, fella.
你們在找什么嗎
You lookin' for something?
他需要點幫助
He could really use a helping hand.
好吧  他可以進去  但只能他一人進去
Yeah, okay, he can go in. But only him.
不行  我也得進去
Uh, no can do. I gotta come with.
除非你也嗑  否則就只有他能進去
Only if you're partaking, otherwise he goes it alone.
給你
Here you go.
30塊
30.
屋里的人會照顧你的
The guy in the house will set you up right.
只要他不殺你的話
Long as he doesn't kill you.
聽著  你一嗑完
All right, look, the minute you're done...
就馬上走
you leave.
你不許看任何人  也不許跟任何人說話
You don't look at anyone. You don't talk to anyone.
你辦完了事  就出來
You take care of business and you get out.
明白就點點頭
Nod if you understand.
想要嗎
You want?
去社會
大眼睛
Big eyes.
沒事的  哥們  來吧
It's all good, man. Go on.
我只是...
I just...
我需要嗎啡  片劑
I need morphine. Pills.
沒辦法
No, man.
我們這里只有這個
This is all we got right here.
這個更好
It's better.
相信我
Trust me.
拿著吧
Go on.
這就對了  這就對了
There you go. There you go.
我幫你
I'll help.
沒事的  我幫你
It'll be okay. I'll help.
我都墮落到這個地步了嗎
Have I sunk this low?
你會怎么想我啊
What must you think of me?
現在是春天了嗎  大選年
Is it spring? Election year?
我該冬眠嗎
Shall I hibernate?
我們見過嗎  我們信任金錢
Did we meet? In money we trust.
不對  我創造了...停下
No, I created-- stop.
我無法控制思緒  我需要這個
I can't control thoughts. I need this.
我知道我保證過那是最后一條  但是...
I know I promised my last line, but...
好了吧
That's right.
不要臉的
Greedy bitch!
該死
Shit, man--
周三  周四  周五
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday,
以下是三州地區的七日預報
here's that seven-day forecast for the tri-state area.
今日多云  但周四基本晴朗
Lots of clouds today, but mostly sunny through Thursday
氣溫偏高  可達26度多
with temperatures in the mid to the upper 80s.
并且濕度會稍稍使人感到不適
And you will notice that the humidity will be a tad uncomfortable.
七日預報
親愛的兄弟姐妹們
Dear brothers and sisters,
現在該睜開眼睛了
now is the time to open your eyes.
如果你尚未覺醒  看清現實中
If you have not yet woken up to the reality of
我們所指出的不正當牟利和奴役
profiteering and enslavement we've been warning you about,
希望你明白  你很快就要沒時間了
I hope you realize you are fast running out of time.
世界各國的政府和其大公司主人
The governments of the world and their corporate masters
不希望我們發聲
do not want us to speak.
為什么  因為我們挖掘真相
Why? Because we unlock truths.
我們曝光惡人  我們處決惡魔
We expose villains. We exorcize demons.
世界公民們  我們是來幫忙的
Citizens of the world, we are here to help.
如果你們想從沉睡中蘇醒
If you have any interest in waking from your slumber,
想找回遺失  受損或被盜取的記憶
in retrieving lost, damaged, or stolen memory,
那我們會幫忙
we are here for you.
我們會照顧你  我們是去社會
We have your back. We are fsociety.
這是打開什么的
What's it open?
現在歸你了
It belongs to you now.
遠東制造
Made in the orient.
專為你的腦袋打造的
Made just for your head.
找到你的怪物  轉動鑰匙
Now, find your monster, then turn the key.
但首先
But first...
我們的公司財閥有話要說
a word from our corporate overlords!
如果您看到了我們的標志  那代表您可以放心
If you see our logo, that means you can rest assured
您正在購買最優質的食品
that you're buying the best food,
衣物  居所
clothing, shelter,
交通工具  衛生設施  電器
transportation, hygiene, electronics,
以及其他生活必需品
and life's necessities that money can buy.
奧德森家  404
404錯誤
地址不存在
你好
Hello.
你好  朋友
Hello, friend.
但我們不是朋友
But we're not friends.
能告訴我這房子怎么了嗎
Can you tell me what happened to that house?
你先告訴我  你的怪物是什么
First can you tell me? What's your monster?
這是你掉的吧
I think you dropped this.
別害羞嘛
Don't be shy now.
靠近點
You can come closer.
我知道  令人不安
Unsettling, I know.
你的寵物魚居然在跟你說話
Your pet beta fish chatting you up.
但時間是金錢  艾略特
But time's money, Elliot.
你想要什么嗎
You need something?
水需要換了嗎
Your water-- does it need changing?
生活在魚缸里  根本就沒什么"變"可言
When you live in a fishbowl, ain't no such thing as change.
我這輩子一直待在這里面
My entire life's been spent in this thing.
我的整個世界就在你小桌上
My whole world's on your side table.
我環顧四周  每一天都一樣
I look around-- same shit, different day.
燈光  家具
The lighting, the furniture.
甚至聲音  總是一樣的
Even the sounds-- always the same.
我處于循環之中
I'm on a loop,
除非我死去  循環無法停止
and it won't stop unless my life does.
我受夠了這世界
I'm exhausted with this world.
我能做什么  我想幫忙
What can I do? I wanna help.
我覺得這很明顯吧
I think it's pretty obvious.
你也就只能為一只魚缸里的
There's really only one thing you can do
黑魚做一件事
for a brother in a fishbowl.
是什么
What is it?
把他搬到窗邊
Move him to a goddamn window!
安吉拉  他是我的朋友啊
Angela, he's my friend.
是啊
Yes.
他很好吃
And he's delicious.
來
Here.
吃下去
Eat this.
張嘴
Open.
非常燙  吃的時候請小心
It's piping hot, so consume with caution.
爸爸著名的樹莓派  慢用
Pop's famous raspberry pie. Enjoy.
愿意
Yes.
我愿意
Yes!
我愿意  艾略特
Yes, Elliot, I do.
艾略特  我愿意
Elliot, I do!
我愿意
I do!
剛剛那些人
Those people in there...
我只是說了他們想聽的
I just told them what they wanted to hear.
你不會那么做的  是吧
You're not gonna do it, are you?
改變世界
Change the world.
猜到了  你才一個月大
Figures. You were only born a month ago.
你害怕
You're afraid.
害怕你的怪物
Afraid of your monster.
你知道那是什么嗎
Do you even know what it is?
不配套
It doesn't fit.
為什么
Why not?
這還不明顯嗎
Isn't it obvious?
你不是艾略特
You're not Elliot.
你是...
You're the--
有人嗎
Hello?
我還是一個人嗎
Am I still alone?
這是我唯一的朋友的臉孔嗎
Is this the face of my only friend?
你是我的怪物嗎
Are you my monster?
我在這兒  你是一個人
I am here. You are alone.
他們都走了
They all left.
我是一個人
I'm alone.
不  不是的
No, you're not.
我哪都不會去的  孩子
I'm not going anywhere, kiddo.
我們會一起走到底
We're in this to the end.
你還是好好走路吧  你似乎不太會跳芭蕾
Maybe you should just walk. Ballet seems out of your skill set.
什么  去你的  小丫頭
What? Screw you, young'un!
老子的曲膝不比任何人差
This bitch can plie with the best of 'em.
我沒忙著敲鍵盤的時候
You know, when I'm not bangin' on a keyboard,
我就在教同學這樣的舞步
I'm schooling classmates with moves like this!
天吶
Oh, my God.
多謝搭救
Good lookin' out.
很遺憾他沒來
I'm sorry he never came.
我們走吧
Let's--let's just go.
我是社會禍害
I am a menace to society!
怎么了
What?
-等等  你去哪  -是他
- Wait, where are you going? - It's him.
手機  馬上拿來
Phone. Now!
給他
Come on.
奧利
我怎么還在外面
Why am I still out?
再過4小時  我就得去上班了
I have to be at work - in four hours!
我會十分懷念這份工作的
There's a lot I'm gonna miss about this gig.
你今后要怎么掙錢啊
What are you gonna do for money now?
就是...去做個性感服務員唄
Oh, you know. Just be a hottie waitress.
我...謝謝
I'm, uh-- oh, thank you.
很高興你喜歡
Glad you liked it.
不過我很高興打工掙錢之前
Although I am glad I got in one last hurrah
還能再這么玩一次
before going all corporate.
你不擔心嗎
You're not worried?
擔心什么
Worried about what?
我說不清
I don't know.
開始新工作之前我總會很擔心
I always get worried before starting a new job.
不  我絕對不擔心
No. I am definitely not worried.
擔心是浪費時間
Worry's a waste of time.
這份工作不合適  我就另找一份
I mean, shit didn't work out at one job, so I got another.
就這樣
That's all!
你經常擔心  是吧
You worry a lot, don't you?
嗯
Yeah.
看鏡子
Look in the mirror.
看到那個狠角色了嗎
See that badass bitch?
她是你這輩子唯一該擔心的人
That's the only person you should ever worry about.
你知道我找你找得多辛苦嗎
Do you know how hard it's been for me to find you?
過來
Come here.
你冷靜點
Yo, you need to chill.
去死吧  混蛋
Go to hell, asshole!
這才像話
There she is.
我黑暗空虛的生活中的一縷陽光
A ray of sunshine in the dark void of my existence.
真詩意
Oh, poetic.
但這不叫道歉
But not an apology.
我才不想道歉呢
I ain't apologizing for shit.
是因為我甩了你嗎
Oh, this is because I dumped your ass.
告訴你  你要惹火我了
For real? You're gonna start pissing me off.
抱歉我想跟你共度一生
Sorry I wanted to spend my life with you.
我真混蛋死了
What a monster I am.
有大事要發生了  西斯科
Things are happening, Cisco.
我們明天就得行動
We need to go tomorrow.
這是唯一的機會
It's our only shot.
那你就沒機會了
Then you never had one.
我說真的  達琳
Look, I'm serious, Darlene.
這些人不是鬧著玩的
These guys don't mess around.
不管你以為你在做什么
Now, whatever it is you think you're doing--
解放世界  解救眾生
freeing the world, freeing the masses--
雇我的人
the guys I work for,
他們的動機可不是那么高尚
they ain't motivated by kumbaya shit like that.
我警告你
All right? Now, I'm warning you...
最后一次警告你
for the last time.
得了
Oh, come on.
你知道這對我多重要
You know how much this means to me.
求你
Please...
跟他們談談
Just talk to them.
我姑媽艾斯特的惡習都用這個治好的
My aunt Esther cured all her habits with this--
液體抗腹瀉劑  治你的...那個
liquid anti-diarrheal for the--well, you know.
檸檬和鹽補充電解質
Lemon and salt for the electrolytes,
解充血藥止鼻涕
decongestant for the runny nose.
這都第三杯了
This is the third one.
再來七杯  你就精神煥發了
Seven more, you'll be good as new.
我去把車開過來
I'm gonna go pull the van around.
讓他繼續喝
Make sure he keeps chugging those.
謝謝
Thanks.
不客氣
Cool.
又見了
Hello again.
好幾沒...
Long time no...
做我們做的事了
whatever it is we do.
我想你了  你去哪了
I missed you. Where did you go?
是你走開了  還是我
Did you leave, or did I?
或許我們都走開了
Maybe it was both.
也或者都沒  無所謂了
Or neither. Doesn't matter.
那些充滿希望的時刻嚇到我了嗎
Did those hopeful moments scare me?
當然了  后臺程序  記得嗎
Of course. Daemons, remember?
早晚  會有一項"無需用戶操作程序"
At some point an "action without user interaction"
出現  讓我措手不及
will come along and sweep my legs.
虛高真低的轉盤會繼續轉動
This spinning wheel of false highs and true lows will continue.
這我確定
That much I know.
后臺程序  他們不會停止運轉
Daemons-- they don't stop working.
他們總是活躍的
They're always active.
他們誘惑  操控
They seduce. They manipulate.
他們主宰我們
They own us.
盡管你在我身邊
And even though you're with me,
盡管我創造了你  也無所謂
even though I created you, it makes no difference.
我們都得獨自面對他們
We all must deal with them alone.
我們最多只能期望
The best we can hope for--
這一切之中唯一的希望
the only silver lining in all of this--
就是我們撐過去時
is that when we break through,
會看到有幾個熟人
we find a few familiar faces
在那邊等我們
waiting on the other side.